# **Kevin Pilcher**

#### Head of ERP Services at Ladbrokes

kevinpilcher@btinternet.com

## Summary

Successful systems delivery & Programme Director with extensive experience in managing full application lifecycle management for Finance, HR, Procurement, Supply Chain, SSCs & Information Management. Experienced at driving cross-disciplinary technology and business teams to design and deliver technical & business solutions whilst ensuring that project parameters of scope, time, quality and cost are well managed. Extensive experience in managing large teams across multiple geographies & managing large projects and multiple project programmes delivering circa £25m benefits. Extensive experience in managing Oracle ERP & IBM major delivery projects in FTSE 100 Telecoms & technology companies.

#### **Key Attributes**

- Director level experience gained in complex blue chip organisations, FTSE 100 companies.
- Delivered major business and IT projects for Finance, HR, Customer Service, Procurement & SSCs driving a focus on challenging benefit realisation.
- Successful at delivering Software as a Service Solutions (Saas), Oracle ERP & IBM Information Management systems.
- Experienced in delivering organisation change, growth & operational excellence projects including assessments and implementation of projects to support merger and acquisition integration activities.
- Skilled at managing relationships at Board level & building alliances across diverse groups of stakeholders to ensure co-operative working relationships between the Business and CIO functions.
- Experienced in managing large multi functional complex teams across multiple geographies (UK, Europe, US, Canada, India) including Vendor Management of both on & offshore Delivery Teams.
- Managed the Vendor selection process for multiple services and projects.
- Industry contributor through conferencing speaking and Technology provider relationships.
- Member of IBM Executive Advisory Board on Sales Performance Management & Oracle Fusion HCM Customer Advisory group.

# Experience

### Head of HRIS/ERP Services at Ladbrokes Coral Group plc

February 2017 - Present (2 months)

#### Head of ERP Services at Ladbrokes

May 2015 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Responsible for all People Systems and Oracle Financials working with HR in a strong matrix with Finance alongside Managed Service Providers and an Internal team.

Transferred into Production handed over from the Programme Team to the new ERP Services Team after just over 2 years - Kronos 7, Oracle e-Business Suite HCM & Payroll 12.2 and taken on responsibility for Oracle Financials 12.1.3.

A very busy initial 8 months.

## Senior Manager, Corporate and Information Management Systems at Colt Technology Services October 2011 - September 2014 (3 years)

Responsible for Corporate & Information Management Systems portfolio reporting into the CIO. Managing a large team in the UK & India delivering application support & development services with budget responsibility for £6m & annual project budget of £10m, covering delivery of application changes and support of more than 25 different Applications both On-Premise and Software as a Service.

Major achievements include:

- Delivered Information Management Technology refresh (Data Warehouse, ETL Tools and Business Objects 4) delivering performance and service improvements, through joint Internal and Vendor Managed Programme Team.
- Delivered Oracle Fusion Human Capital Management (HCM) application as SaaS following selection to replace other HR Applications over 3 years as they reach end of life
- Achieved the Process/System Design Study & recommended the approach for Upgrade to Oracle e-Business Suite R12 ratified by Vendor partners and with Oracle EVP for Application Delivery. Undertaken reviews with other ERP vendors as replacement for Oracle ERP (SAP, Netsuite)
- Programme Managed implementation of 3rd Party Logistics Supply Chain solution with full integration between ERP and Logistics Partner solution delivering savings and opportunities to reduce inventory holdings.
- Responsible for the selection and integration of new Global Payroll Service, replacing multiple Country solutions to standardise payroll processes across Colt (18 Countries).

#### Senior Programme Manager at Colt Technology Services

August 2008 - October 2011 (3 years 3 months)

Recruited as Senior Programme Manager with following key achievements:

• Reduced the cost base of ERP Management post upgrade to Oracle 11i by removing Consultants & by building a team of Colt employees in the UK & India.

- Implemented Successfactors HR Application and integrated with Core Oracle HR Data in 6 months of Vendor selection.
- Replaced an in-House Sales Commission Application with Vendor solution saved circa €150k in Development cost in first year and reduced the number of people involved in the process by more than 40% within 2 years of implementation.

#### Programme Manager - Openreach CIO at BT

February 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 4 months)

Ensured the successful delivery of business benefits and transformational activity, managing a portfolio of changes for Finance, HR and Customer Services of circa £10 million in the current year delivering £23m benefits. Partnering with Senior Executives, at Managing Director and Director Level, across a portfolio of Business Change Initiatives. Delivering solutions designed to solve business problems using new working methods, underpinned by IT systems and changed working processes.

- Initiated Delivery of Oracle E-Business Finance and Billing Systems changes to improve reporting and controls for Chief Finance Officer for compliance to Sarbanes-Oxley.
- Managed evaluation of new Business Change Requirements and development of Solution Design and confirmation of agreed business benefits with Stakeholders, as part of Business Case development including Oracle Project Management tools to manage change programmes.
- Successfully programme managed Customer Service Management system projects across multiple sites in the UK and India delivering benefits of more than £12m in the current year, including Genesys Contact Centre applications.
- Delivered Integrated Voice Management platform to Service Management for more than 1000 users across 10 sites.
- Matrix management of Programme/Senior Project Managers from in-house supply team and also third party on and off-shore vendors.
- Managed relationship between Business Unit, Application Developers and Desktop Solution Vendor upgrading equipment for Openreach Business users maintaining an awareness of trials in new mobile equipment for Operational Engineers.
- Managed successful relationships, stakeholder communication and involvement; reporting progress, risks and issues whilst developing the Systems Strategy roadmap accordingly to maximise component reuse.

### Multiple Positions in Finance, Billing and IT at BT

August 1979 - May 2008 (28 years 10 months)

#### Senior Finance Systems Manager – Global & Corporate Finance at BT

April 2003 - March 2005 (2 years)

Programme management responsibility for the Global Services Oracle E-Business/Finance systems strategy and associated expenditure.

• Developed and delivered the strategy to consolidate disparate Oracle and other local Finance Systems within BT Global Services into European Oracle e-Business Single Instance

- Managed a matrix team across Business units and Systems teams to implement Oracle Financials system and associated processes, migrating 7 countries to a common platform subsequently successfully audited for financial compliance by External Auditors
- Managed Oracle Finance Systems and associated Process requirements for the integration of new acquisitions with a variety of customers (Finance, IT and Business representatives), negotiated stakeholder differences into an integrated requirement that satisfied all.
- Programme Managed Conference Room Pilot of Oracle 11.5.10 expenses and Credit card integration through to stage of gathering final requirements from the Business and Third Party Shared Service Business Partners (left team to join Openreach).

### Head of Finance System (Oracle 11i) & Process Transformation at BT Global Services

April 2002 - April 2003 (1 year 1 month)

Managed the conclusion of BT's Global Venture with AT&T. Responsible for integrating people and process transition back to BT Global Services.

- Transitioned and integrated the systems requirements of over 2000 people to BT Group plc following the closure of the Global Venture between BT and AT&T.
- Programme managed the closure and outsourcing of the EMEA Shared Service Centre for approx. 30 entities using Oracle Financials and PeopleSoft HR. Negotiating with Vendors and maintaining goodwill and performance of team at the site being made redundant.
- Managed systems integration challenges of returning more than 2000 people to BT Group.
- Advised BT Group stakeholders on integration issues.

## Senior Finance Manager - Concert Communications at BT and AT&T Global Venture

January 2000 - March 2002 (2 years 3 months)

Project managed the creation of processes and systems to track Capital and Development expenditure. Delivered processes & training to support global users for new Global Business with capital expenditure budget in excess of \$1.5 billion US Dollars using Oracle Project Accounting fully integrated into Oracle e-Business Suite.

- Managed implementation and operation of Oracle Project Accounting system and related applications & processes controlling Capital & Development expenditure fully integrating with Oracle Financials and Procurement modules.
- Managed a multi-cultural team based across UK and US.
- Supported and encouraged the development of training material on Finance transaction processes and delivery to operational users globally. Improved accuracy of accounting records.
- Advised BT Group on the transition and development of on-going commercial relationships and validation of charging structures between Concert and BT Group.

**Offshoring** 

**Vendor Management** 

**Cross-functional Team Leadership** 

**Project Delivery** 

**Stakeholder Management** 

**Project Portfolio Management** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Business Intelligence** 

**Data Migration** 

**Oracle E-Business Suite** 

**Shared Service Center** 

**Matrix Management** 

**Software Lifecycle Management** 

SaaS

**Solution Architecture** 

**Business Process** 

**Project Planning** 

**Outsourcing** 

**Project Management** 

**Service Delivery** 

**Integration** 

Management

**Change Management** 

**Telecommunications** 

**Program Management** 

**IT Operations** 

**Oracle** 

**IT Service Management** 

**Team Management** 

**Service Management** 

**Strategy** 

**Business Transformation** 

SAP

**IT Strategy** 

**Software Project Management** 

Sla

**Business Process Improvement** 

**PMP** 

**IT Management** 

**Pre-sales** 

Governance

**Resource Management** 

**Enterprise Architecture** 

Professional Services Business Case IT Outsourcing Cloud Computing

# Education

### **University of Hertfordshire**

Diploma in Management Studies, Business, 1994 - 1996

## **South East London Technical College**

HNC in Business Studies and Finance, Business Studies, 1979 - 1984

#### Sittingbourne

1973 - 1978

## **Teynham Primary School**

1967 - 1973

# Certifications

**Member of the Association of Project Managers** 

# **Kevin Pilcher**

Head of ERP Services at Ladbrokes

kevinpilcher@btinternet.com



# 2 people have recommended Kevin

"Kevin has a highly informed and pragmatic approach to all engagements. His depth of knowledge on ERP and his command of the complexities associated with running, maintaining and innovating ERP to meet business needs is exemplary. He couples this with a amenable, and highly professional manner. A pleasure to do business with."

— Peter Nuttall, was with another company when working with Kevin at Colt Technology Services

"Kevin was my mentor while at Concert Communications. It was because of his knowledge, guidance and direction and that lead to our teams success at Concert. He was one of the best manager's that I ever worked with, which includes my tenure at AT&T as well as Concert. He is goal oriented and instills individuals to be the best that they can be in the completion of their responsibilities as well as establishment and completion of endeavors that contribute to the corporate's bottom line."

— Mikey Frontczak, reported to Kevin at BT

Contact Kevin on LinkedIn